Contact

- Bandırma, Balıkesir, 10200
- 545-516-2688
- mertcanerbasiemk@gma il.com
- https://www.linkedin.co m/in/mertcan-erba%C5 %9Fi-46

Skills

SQL



PostgreSQL



Intelligence gathering



Statistical analysis



Machine learning



Computer skills



Written Communication



Data management



Microsoft Office





Hello,

Working as a Data Scientist familiar with gathering, cleaning and organizing data for use by technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of statistical, algebraic and other analytical techniques. Highly organized, motivated and diligent with significant background in Data Science. Besides, have got over 2 years of experience in ML. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

Work History

2019-11 -Current

Data Scientist

Koçtaş, Istanbul, 34

- Provided comprehensive analysis and recommend solutions to address complex business problems and issues using data from internal and external sources and applied advanced analytical methods to assess factors impacting growth and profitability across product and service offerings.
- Developed quarterly roadmaps based on impact, effort and test coordinations, working with stakeholders to achieve short-term and long-term goals.
- Designed and automated more than 50 innovative digitization and online marketing report tools and dashboards based on key performance indicators for different management levels, leading to increased transparency and sales performance.
- Used Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms to analyze and solve complex business problems.
- Applied statistical and algebraic techniques to

	Excellent	
Critical thinking		2019-03 -
	Excellent	2019-09
Python		
	Excellent	
R		
	Good	
Visualization tech	nniques	
	Very Good	2018-08 - 2019-03

Languages



2018-05 -2018-07 interpret key points from gathered data.

Data Science Intern

Otokoç Otomotiv

- Job definition was fundamentally defining and creating some sense over big data. While working there, learnt so much things about programming and especially data mining- analysis from experts.
- However, most importantly i gained really good relationships and taste of working with good team who are trying to improve knowledge of their mates and help them emotionally.

Human Resources Analyst Intern

Turkish Airlines A.O.

- My job definition was creating and implementing some usefull data tools for help the HR experts to choose best qualificated candicates besides of examining the current situation of the company to create much more effect on the bussiness logic.
- Also, i had a lot of fun here with my teammates
 They shared their experiences with me in HR and improved my vision rather than keep focusing on computers and engineering, they literally showed me a different side of organizations, the human side.
- I got proud of working there and with that people so much.

Data Analyst Intern

- I created various tools to add some speed the organizations processes.
- Generally used python (numpy, matlib, opency for defining the content of the pdf's).
- I had a lot of fun with working there and my mates.
- But it was a project based job and i had to go back istanbul for my school.
- EDUCATION Data Analysis.

Education

2015-09 - Bachelor of Science: Industrial Engineering

Istanbul Technical University - Istanbul

- Relevant Coursework Completed: ML
 Implementations in Business & Advance Python
- Member of IEEE
- Professional development completed in ML
- Dean's List 2020

Accomplishments

- PROJECTS Robotic Process Automation for Business Performance Evaluation Bot I developed that project for OTOKOÇ Human Resources department. Fundamentals of that project is: Python Based Quickening the performance evaluation of the employees (Approximately 3 day to 30 seconds) Has Graphical User Interface in order to make it easier to use Text Mining Bot That project is developed in Turkish Airlines in order to make an analysis over the big data. Also, that project used NiFi as a big data tool.
- Graduation Thesis I developed an Android application in order to track, detect the smartphone addiction. That project is created with Java and Android Studio. To summarize that project: It implies 3 test to the user at the beginning in order to collect the data of the current situation. After that starts the backend service and track the user smartphone usage behaviour. Detect patterns and creates notifications if limits of normal usage exceeds. Focus of the project is eliminating the psychological factors that leads the user to the addiction.
- Worked as a Data Scientist in a project which named 'Analytics on Retail (AIR)'. In that project we used, Azure, Python, Xtract Universal, SAP BW

together. Architecture was get the data from SAP BW and extract it to Azure with Xtract Universal and analyze it with Python and create sales prediction on the basis of 4-12-52 weeks. After that I also participated in creating PowerBI reports which are created to show the results of that algorithm.

Certifications

2019-09

2021-03	OpenHack Al Training
2021-01	Intermediate R

Intermediate Python for Data Science